双语特效字幕
百度贴吧衣柜字幕组
专注GOT剧集 华语冰火最专业字幕
翻译 小愤青菜
翻译 reasno
翻译 猇亭将
君临 King's Landing
翻译 barossa
红堡
Red Keep
校对 拉拉兄控凯冯
校对 泰温公爵
龙石岛 Dragonstone
恐怖堡 Dreadfort
临冬城 Winterfell
后期  窝鹏偏逢连夜雪
后期 Jeremy
时间轴 poplar
监制 临冬城的狮子
监制 托曼·兰尼斯特
监制 北落师门
策划 baozhenyuawabi
特别顾问 屈畅(ccxx)@史诗图书
绝境长城 the Wall
最专业的华语冰火资料站：冰与火之歌中文维基
http://zh.asoiaf.wikia.com/
百度冰与火之歌贴吧 & 百度权力的游戏贴吧  联合出品
弥林Meereen
根据长篇小说
《冰与火之歌》 改编
原著  乔治·R·R·马丁
权力的游戏
第四季 第二集
衣柜字幕组
史诗图书 正统奇幻的圣殿
更多冰火奇幻咨询 关注黑城堡微信平台
第二集  The Lion and the Rose
王家婚礼
艾菊!艾菊!
Tansy! Tansy!
艾菊!
Tansy!
我看不到她的身影了 拉姆斯
I can't see her, Ramsay.
艾菊!
Tansy!
如果能逃出这片树林 就算你赢了！
If you make it out of the woods, you win!
跑啊 艾菊 快跑啊！
Run, Tansy, run!
- 艾菊 - 她在哪里？
- Tansy.- Where is she?
艾菊 艾菊 艾菊!
Tansy, Tansy, Tansy!
真是乖狗狗 安静点 乖狗狗
Good girls. Down, girls.
乖
Down.
干得不错 你也是
Well done. You, too.
- 我只是射伤了她 - 你把她放倒了 这才是关键
- I only wounded her. - You brought her down. That's what matters.
射得真精彩 不是吗 臭佬?
A fine shot. Wasn't it, Reek?
拉姆斯·雪诺
卢斯·波顿的私生子
“臭佬”
席恩·葛雷乔伊
的确如此 老爷 小姐
A fine shot, master. My lady.
饶了我吧 大人 好疼啊
Please, my lord. It hurts.
噢 宝贝儿 别哭
Oh, sweet. Don't cry.
很快就会结束的
It will be over soon.
她以为她很漂亮
She thinks she's pretty.
让我射在她脸上吧
Let me put one through her face.
我们得犒劳下猎狗们 亲爱的
We have to reward the hounds, love.
累活儿都是它们做的
They did all the hard work.
为什么对我这么残忍? 我可是对您百依百顺
Why? I did whatever you asked.
但你让米兰达吃醋了
But you made Myranda feel jealous.
- 吃她的醋? - 别说笑了 大人
- Me jealous of her? - My lord, please.
你也知道 你错就错在长得漂亮
You can see that your presence has become a bit of a problem.
撕烂她! 咬碎她!
Rip her! Rip her!
现在可就没那么漂亮了
Not so pretty now.
提利昂·兰尼斯特
“小恶魔” 财政大臣
詹姆·兰尼斯特
“弑君者” 御林铁卫队长
你的新手 看着比旧的顺眼嘛
Your new hand, it's nicer than the old one.
你不这么想吗 波德?
Wouldn't you agree, Pod?
波德瑞克·派恩
提利昂的侍从
它是纯金的吗?
Is it solid gold?
钢镀金而已 你怎么也不吃东西
Gilded steel. You're not eating.
怎么都没有人吃东西呢?
Why is no one eating?
我老婆日渐消瘦 我哥也在绝食
My wife wastes away and my brother starves himself.
- 我不饿 - 你失去的是一只手
- I'm not hungry. - You lost a hand,
不是胃
not a stomach.
吃点野猪肉吧
Try the boar.
野猪顶死劳勃后 瑟熙就吃野猪肉吃个不停
Cersei can't get enough of it since one killed Robert for her.
举杯
A toast.
敬兰尼斯特家族姐弟们
To the proud Lannister children.
敬侏儒 残废 和疯婆子
The dwarf, the cripple, and the mother of madness.
- 哦! - 让我来清理干净
- Oh! - I'll clean it up.
不用了 我来 你退下吧
No, I'll do it. Leave us.
只是红酒而已
It's only wine.
我再也不能作战了
I can't fight anymore.
你的左手怎么样?
What about your left?
我能拿住剑 但完全找不到感觉
I can hold a sword, but all my instincts are wrong.
我该如何保护国王呢
How can I protect the king
我连自己擦屁股都成问题
when I can hardly wipe my own ass?
你现在可是铁卫队长 放心吧
You're the Lord Commander now. Come on.
让手下去作战不就得了
Let others do the fight.
你能记得父亲上次拔剑是什么时候？
When was the last time Father used a sword?
我不是咱们身为国王之手的父亲 我是弑君者
I'm not Father. I'm the Kingslayer.
要是人们发现我连只鸽子都弑不掉……
When people find out I can't slay a pigeon...
那就训练啊 练习用另一只手去作战
Train, then. Learn to fight with your other hand.
跟谁?你吗?人们会说三道四的
With whom? You? Men talk.
一旦有人察觉到我已经不能作战 就会人尽皆知
Soon as someone discovers I can't fight, he'll tell everyone.
得找一个靠谱的剑客来训练你
You need a proper, discreet swordsman.
其实我就有合适的人选
As it happens, I have just the one.
我弟弟告诉我说你能守口如瓶
My brother tells me you can keep your mouth shut.
这能耐对于佣兵来说可不常见
Unusual talent for a sellsword.
他还告诉我你能拉黄金屎呢
He tells me you shit gold
跟你父亲一样
just like your father.
这地方安全吗?
Is this place safe?
波隆
骑士
曾有个雷古德家族的骑士
There's a knight, Leygood,
- 你知道吗?家徽上有三道闪电那个 - 嗯
- got thunderbolts on his shield? - Uh- huh.
我就在这里干了他老婆
Right here is where I fuck his wife.
她不停地尖叫
She's a screamer, that one.
他们听不见她的尖叫 自然也听不到我们的声音
If they don't hear her, they won't hear us.
我第一次见到瓦雷利亚钢打造的剑
I've never seen Valyrian steel before.
真漂亮啊 问题是
She's a beauty.The problem is,
如果你要用开刃的剑跟我打斗
if you fight with an edged blade,
我只能接受
I'll have to.
而如果我用开刃的剑跟你打斗
And if I fight with an edged blade,
可就没人付我工钱了
I'll have no one left to pay me.
我九岁起就没使过练习用的钝剑了
I haven't used a sparring sword since I was nine.
啊!
Ah!
像你这样英勇的战士 应该不会在对方毫无防备的时候偷袭吧
Bold warrior you are, attacking a man when his guard's down.
那可是袭击的最好时机
Best time to attack a man.
注意!
Mind yourself!
- 但凡我还有右手 也不至于…… - 还准备让它再长出来呗?
- If I still had my right hand... - Plan on growing it back?
再来
Come on, then.
打开城门!
Open the gates!
骑士们回来了!
Riders coming in!
也好好犒劳下我们的马!
Let's get these horses seen to!
父亲 欢迎回家
Father. Welcome home.
卢斯·波顿
恐怖堡公爵
瓦妲·佛雷
"胖子" 瓦德·佛雷的孙女
卢斯·波顿的妻子
瓦妲 这是拉姆斯·雪诺 我的私生子
Walda, this is Ramsay Snow, my bastard.
很荣幸见到您 母亲
A pleasure, Mother.
你好
Hello.
看着他们喂马 饮马 刷马
See that the horses are fed, watered, and rubbed down.
然后领着瓦妲夫人到她的房间去
And take Lady Walda to her chambers.
请走这边 夫人
This way, my lady.
你的战利品在哪里?
Where is your prize?
猎狗们看守着他
With the hounds.
让我看看他
I'll have a look at him.
洛克
我听说你砍下了弑君者的一只手臂
I hear you took a hand from the Kingslayer.
好事传千里啊 他当时疯狂地尖叫
Word travels. How he screamed.
你一定爱死那声音了
You would have loved it.
父亲
Father.
你怎么折磨他的?
What did you do to him?
我在训练他 他学得很慢 但总归有点进步
I trained him. He was a slow learner, but he learned.
你剥了他的皮
You flayed him.
就弄掉了一点儿
Peeled a few bits.
其他地方也弄掉了点儿
Removed a few others.
他可是巴隆·葛雷乔伊的儿子和继承人
This was Balon Greyjoy's son and heir.
我们剥敌人的皮也有上千年了
We've been flaying our enemies for 1,000 years.
红色剥皮人是我们的旗帜
The flayed man is on our banners.
我的旗帜 不是你的
My banners, not yours.
你可不是波顿家的人 你只是个雪诺罢了
You're not a Bolton. You're a Snow.
泰温·兰尼斯特已把北境交给我
Tywin Lannister has given me the North.
但又丝毫不肯帮我来将这里收入囊中
But he won't lift a finger to help me take it.
只要铁民还占着卡林湾
As long as the ironborn hold Moat Cailin,
我们的军队就被卡在颈泽动弹不得
our armies are trapped south of the Neck.
席恩是个很有价值的人质 不能拿他当你的玩物
Theon was a valuable hostage, not your plaything.
我想拿他来换取卡林湾的控制权
I wanted to trade him for Moat Cailin.
我请求过了
I already asked.
葛雷乔伊大人拒绝了我 野蛮人就是没有——
Lord Greyjoy refused. Savages have no--
你未经我同意就去与巴隆·葛雷乔伊谈条件?
You sent terms to Balon Greyjoy without my consent?
是您让我当恐怖堡代理城主的
You made me acting Lord of the Dreadfort.
我照做了
I acted.
我回自己家还得走小道
I had to smuggle myself into my own lands
还不是那些葛雷乔伊家族的人害的
thanks to the Greyjoys.
我需要席恩
I needed Theon.
完整的他
I needed him whole.
席恩是我们的敌人
Theon was our enemy.
但臭佬不同
But Reek,
臭佬永远不会背叛我们
Reek will never betray us.
我对你太过信任了
I placed far too much trust in you.
臭佬 你怎么能让我满脸胡茬就来见我父亲?
Reek, how could you let me stand before my father unshaven?
- 这太失礼了 - 抱歉 大人
- It's disrespectful. - I'm sorry, my lord.
给他剃刀
Give him the razor.
我不姓波顿 父亲 这又有什么关系?
I'm not a Bolton, Father, what does it matter?
继续帮我刮胡子啊 臭佬
Go on, Reek.
轻轻刮 好好刮
A nice close shave.
臭佬 告诉我父亲
Reek, tell Father
布兰跟瑞肯·史塔克到哪里去啦?
where are Bran and Rickon Stark?
我不知道 大人
I don't know, my lord.
你杀害了他们
You murdered them
然后将他们的尸体吊在临冬城城头
and displayed their corpses at Winterfell.
臭佬
Reek,
是你杀了史塔克家的儿子吗?
did you murder the Stark boys?
不是 大人
No, my lord.
那只是两个农户的孩子
Just two farm boys.
但尸体已被烧变形 死无对证
And crisped them so no one would know.
是 大人
Yes, my lord.
史塔克家族一直是北境的统治者
The Starks have always ruled the North.
只要布兰和瑞肯还活着
If Bran and Rickon are alive,
整个北境都会听其号令
the country will rally to their side
现在罗柏·史塔克已死
now that Robb Stark is gone.
哦 对了 臭佬
Oh, that's right, Reek.
罗柏·史塔克已经死了哟
Robb Stark is dead.
我很遗憾
Sorry.
我知道你们情同手足
I know he was like a brother to you.
但是我父亲一刀剜了他的心脏
But my father put a knife through his heart.
你感觉如何？
How do you feel about that?
- 准备好来场追猎了么 - 时刻如此
- You ready for a hunt? - Always.
找到两个男孩 我就封你千亩土地和一座城堡
Find those boys and I'll give you 1,000 acres and a holdfast.
你的玩物知道他们离开临冬城后
Your pet rat have any thoughts
可能会往哪儿去吗？
on which way they went after Winterfell?
琼恩·雪诺在黑城堡
Jon Snow is at Castle Black.
琼恩·雪诺是哪个杂种
Who the fuck is Jon Snow?
他们的私生子哥哥
Their bastard brother.
他可能藏匿他们
He could be sheltering them.
也可能知道他们的踪影
He may know where they are.
就算他不知道 他也是半个史塔克
Even if he doesn't, he's half Stark himself.
是潜在的威胁
Could be a threat.
你想证明你是个波顿？
You want to prove yourself a Bolton?
带你的全部人马向卡林湾进发
Gather whatever men you can and ride for Moat Cailin.
带上你的这个东西
Bring this creature of yours.
也许能顶上用
Maybe he'll be of some use.
为家族拿下卡林湾
Take the Moat for the family,
我们的家族
for our family,
我会重新考虑你的身份
and I'll reconsider your position.
瓦里斯大人 要不要跟国王一起吃早餐
Lord Varys. Breakfasting with the king?
瓦里斯
“八爪蜘蛛” 情报总管
如此盛会恐怕不会欢迎外人
I'm afraid foreigners aren't welcome at such exclusive affairs.
- 哦 你是外人啊 - 嗯哼
- Oh, to be foreign. - Ahem.
雪伊已经引起了注意
Shae has been noticed.
珊莎的侍女看见了你和她在一起
Sansa's maid saw you with her.
她告诉了你姐姐
She already told your sister.
你父亲听说此事只是时间问题
It's only a matter of time before your father hears.
难道我和我妻子的贴身侍女在一起都是有罪的了？
So I'm guilty of being seen with my own wife's handmaiden.
我父亲会问你还有没有其他的事情发生
My father will ask you if there's anything more
而你会告诉他一个机智的谎言
and you'll tell him some clever lie.
不 我不会
No, I will not.
你想想如果你父亲和你姐怀疑我撒谎
How long do you imagine your father and sister would let me live
我还有多少日子可活
if they suspected me of lying?
我可没有如影随行的佣兵保护
I have no pet sellsword to protect me.
也没有传奇般的兄长替我复仇
No legendary brother to avenge me.
我只有在耳边低语的小小鸟们
Only little birds who whisper in my ear.
原谅我不会为你哭泣
Forgive me if I don't weep for you.
没人为蜘蛛或妓女哭泣
No one weeps for spiders or whores.
在狭海彼岸我有朋友能帮她
I have friends across the sea who could help her.
她不肯走
She won't leave.
我早就告诉她这里是一个危险的地方
I've told her this is a dangerous place
说了太多次 她再也不信了
so many times, she no longer believes it.
你父亲说过他会吊死在你身边发现的下一个妓女
Your father has promised to hang the next whore he finds you with.
你可曾听说过你父亲的威胁落空？
Have you ever known your father to make an idle threat?
谨代表提利尔家族和河湾地的人民
From House Tyrell and the people of the Reach,
国王陛下 我很荣幸为你呈上这尊婚礼金杯
Your Grace, it is my honor to present you with this wedding cup.
珊莎·史塔克
小恶魔的妻子
希望您和我的女儿玛格丽
May you and my daughter Margaery
梅斯·提利尔
高庭公爵 玛格丽·提利尔之父
共饮杯中酒 幸福又长寿
drink deep and live long.
瑟曦·兰尼斯特
摄政太后
泰温·兰尼斯特
凯岩城公爵 国王之手
乔佛里·拜拉席恩
铁王座上的王
漂亮的金杯 公爵大人
A handsome goblet, my lord.
也许我该叫你父亲？
Or shall I call you Father?
我很荣幸 陛下
I shall be honored, Your Grace.
雪伊
珊莎的侍女 小恶魔的情人
这就是我跟你提过的那个妓女
She's the whore I told you about.
深色头发那个
The dark- haired one.
在婚礼之前把她带到首相塔
Have her brought to the Tower of the Hand before the wedding.
一本书？
A book?
《四王志》 大学士喀斯所著的史书
"The Lives of Four Kings." Grand Maester Kaeth's history
叙述了少龙主戴伦
of the reigns of Daeron the Young Dragon,
受神祝福的贝勒 庸王伊耿 贤王戴伦四位国王的事迹
Baelor the Blessed, Aegon the Unworthy, and Daeron the Good.
这是每个国王都该读的书
A book every king should read.
既然现在战争已经结束
Now that the war is won,
我们都应该花时间寻求智慧
we should all find time for wisdom.
谢谢 舅舅
Thank you, Uncle.
首都仅有的两把瓦雷利亚钢剑之一
One of only two Valyrian steel swords in the capital,
陛下 为您新近铸造
Your Grace, freshly forged in your honor.
小心 陛下 没有什么和瓦雷利亚钢剑一样锋利
Careful, Your Grace. Nothing cuts like Valyrian steel.
派席尔
大学士
托曼·拜拉席恩
乔佛里之弟 王位继承者
早有耳闻
So they say.
这般神兵应有一个名字
Such a great sword should have a name.
- 我该如何命名？ - 风暴使者
- What shall I call her? - Stormbringer.
- 终结者 - 寡妇的哭嚎
- Terminus. - Widow's Wail.
- 狼魇 - 寡妇的哭嚎 我喜欢
- Wolfsbane. - Widow's Wail. I like that.
每次我挥动此剑 就如同
Every time I use it, it'll be like cutting off
再次砍掉奈德·史塔克的头颅
Ned Stark's head all over again.
不要
Don't.
你想在桌子上要我？
You want me on the desk?
- 怎么了 我的狮子？ - 别这么叫我
- What's wrong, my lion? - Don't call me that.
那我应该怎么叫你？
What should I call you?
恐怕我们的友谊不能再继续下去了
I'm afraid our friendship can't continue.
我们的友谊？
Our friendship?
有艘前往潘托斯的船在海港等你
There's a ship waiting in the harbor bound for Pentos.
什么？
What?
当然 你会有独自的船舱
You'll have your own cabin, of course,
并且在狭海彼岸有一栋房子 下人
and across the Narrow Sea a house, servants.
这是怎么回事
What is this?
我是结了婚的男人
I'm a married man.
我的妻子遭受了很大的打击 相信你很清楚
My wife has suffered a great deal, as you well know.
我不想让她再因我而受更多折磨
I don't want her to suffer anymore on my account.
我须要恪守我的誓言
I need to uphold my vows.
她不想要你
She doesn't want you.
- 我要为她约束自己 - 你不想要她
- I need to do right by her. - You don't want her.
为我们的孩子
By our children.
- 你在害怕什么 - 我不害怕
- What are you afraid of? - I'm not afraid.
- 你害怕 你害怕你的父亲和姐姐
You are. You are afraid of your father and your sister.
- 你要一辈子都逃避他们？ - 我须要你离开
- You're going to run from them all your life? - I need you to leave.
我不怕他们 我不需要逃避
I'm not afraid of them. I'm not going to run.
- 雪伊 - 我们并肩抗争
- Shae. - We will fight them together.
就像你说的那样 我是你的 你是我的
It's like you said, I am yours and you are mine.
你是个妓女！
You're a whore!
珊莎才配为我生子 你不配
Sansa is fit to bear my children and you are not.
我不能爱上一个妓女
I can't be in love with a whore.
我不能和一个妓女生下后代
I can't have children with a whore.
你和多少男人上过床?
How many men have you been with?
500? 5,000?
你和多少个妓女上过床？
How many whores have you been with?
我很享受和她们每一个人在一起的时光
I have enjoyed my time with all of them
而我最享受的是和你在一起的时光
and I have enjoyed my time with you most of all.
但是这段时光已经结束
But now that time is over.
你会在潘托斯过上安逸的生活
You'll have a comfortable life in Pentos.
波隆会带你到船上
Bronn will escort you to your ship.
请接受这些代表我们信仰的礼物吧 光之王
Accept these tokens of our faith, my lord,
梅丽珊卓
光之王的“红袍祭司”
带领我们离开黑暗
and lead us from the darkness.
陛下 我为您鞠躬尽瘁
Sire, I served you well.
史坦尼斯·拜拉席恩
狭海中的王
戴佛斯·席渥斯
“洋葱骑士” 史坦尼斯的首相
亚赛尔·佛罗伦
赛丽丝·佛罗伦的兄弟
赛丽丝 你是我的妹妹
Selyse, you're my sister!
赛丽丝·佛罗伦
史坦尼斯·拜拉席恩之王后
你是引导我们的明星
Yours are the stars that guide us.
告诉他！ 告诉他！
Tell him! Tell him!
光之王 保佑我们
Lord of Light, protect us,
因为长夜黑暗 处处险恶
for the night is dark and full of terrors.
你看见了吗？ 他们的灵魂
Did you see? Their souls.
这是他们的灵魂
It was their souls.
吾主带走了他们 你看到了吗
Our lord took them. Did you see?
佛罗伦大人是您的内兄
Lord Florent was your brother by law.
他是个异端
He was an infidel.
他膜拜他父辈的神灵
He worshipped the gods of his fathers
以及父辈的父辈
and their fathers before him.
那些也是您父辈的神灵
They were the gods of your fathers, too.
我命令他推倒他的神像
I ordered him to tear down his idols.
他拒绝了
He disobeyed.
他将多少艘战船带到您的麾下？
How many ships did he bring to your cause?
多少士兵？
How many men?
比你多不少
A good deal more than you.
你看见了吗 戴佛斯爵士
Did you see, Ser Davos?
他们现在与吾主同在
They're with our lord now.
他们的罪孽已经全部化作灰烬 你看见了吗
Their sins all burned away. Did you see?
我相信他们一定感激涕零 王后殿下
I'm sure they're more than grateful, my queen.
把肉撤了
Meat's off.
我们贮藏室几乎空了
Our larders are almost empty.
那就吃鱼 我们在一座岛上
Serve fish, then. We're on an island.
你讨厌鱼
You hate fish.
我讨厌的东西多了 还不是一样要忍受
I hate a good many things, but I suffer them all the same.
当风息堡被围攻时 我深受饥饿之苦
When Storm's End was under siege and I was starving,
史坦尼斯用书为我熬汤
Stannis boiled soup for me from books.
粘书的胶是从马身上来的
The binding glue is made from horses.
一天早上 他在沙滩上射中两只海鸥
One morning, he shot two seagulls on the beach.
我再未品尝过任何比烤海鸥更美味的食物了
I've never tasted anything as good as grilled seagull.
- 你还记得吗？ - 我当然记得
- Do you remember? - Of course I remember.
你是否知道真正的饥饿 夫人
Have you ever known true hunger, my lady?
当我还是个孩子 这是我唯一知道的事
It's all I knew when I was a child.
直到你发现了光之王？
Until you found the Lord of Light?
直到他发现了我
Until he found me.
我担心我们女儿的灵魂
I fear for our daughter's soul.
每个母亲都有理由担心自己孩子的灵魂
Every mother should fear for her child's soul.
- 她是个倔强的野兽 - 她是个孩子
- She's a stubborn little beast. - She's a child.
你几乎不了解她
You barely know her.
你觉得她可爱是因为她只拿笑脸对着你
You think she's sweet because she smiles when you visit.
她阴沉 固执 罪孽深重
She's sullen and stubborn and sinful.
否则为何光之王在她的脸上打上烙印？
Why else would the Lord of Light have seen fit to mark her face?
她需要棍棒伺候
She needs the rod.
她是我的女儿 你不能打她
She's my daughter. You will not strike her.
遵命
As you command.
也许梅丽珊卓女士可以和她谈谈
Perhaps the Lady Melisandre could speak with her.
希琳·拜拉席恩
史坦尼斯·拜拉席恩的女儿
进来
Come in.
你在睡觉吗 公主?
Were you sleeping, Princess?
你看到了沙滩上的仪式了吗？
Did you watch the ceremony on the beach?
我听到了
I heard it.
它吓着你了？
And it frightened you?
亚赛尔爵士是我舅舅
Ser Axel was my uncle.
他总是对我很友好
He was always kind to me.
他们现在去了更好的地方 公主
They're in a better place now, Princess.
火焰净化他们世间的罪恶
The fire cleansed them of the sins of the world.
但是他们尖叫了
But they screamed.
女人在生孩子的时候也尖叫
Women scream when they give birth.
之后却满心欢喜
Afterward they are filled with joy.
之后他们不是灰烬和骨头
Afterward they aren't ash and bone.
你总是满腹疑惑 不是吗?
You have so many questions, don't you?
我小时候也是
So did I when I was a child.
我和你差不多
I was much like you.
不过我却不是公主
Only I wasn't a princess.
你也没有这个
And you didn't have this.
是的
No.
但是我忍受的是另一种苦 小可爱 相信我
But I suffered in other ways, sweet girl, believe me.
关于神你知道多少
What do you know of the gods?
我读过《七星圣经》
I read "The Seven- Pointed Star.”
都是谎言和杜撰
Lies and fables.
主教们宣讲七神
Septons speak of seven gods.
但神只有两位-
There are but two—
一位带来爱和欢乐的光之神
a god of light and love and joy
以及一位带来邪恶和恐惧的黑暗之神
and a god of darkness, evil, and fear.
永远在交战
Eternally at war.
所以也没有七神天堂和七重地狱？
There are no seven heavens and no seven hells?
只有一个地狱 公主
There's only one hell, Princess.
我们正生活在其中
The one we live in now.
布兰·史塔克
易形者
为什么叫醒我？
Why did you wake me?
梅拉·黎德
布兰·史塔克的保护者
玖健·黎德
拥有绿之视野的男孩
阿多
临冬城的马僮
你都“去”了好几个小时了
You've been gone for hours.
我饿了
I was hungry.
我们都饿了
We're all hungry.
我正吃东西呢
I was just eating.
是夏天在吃东西
Summer was eating.
你自己是不能靠狼吃的东西过活的
Your body can't live on the food your wolf consumes.
附在夏天身上这么久很危险
Spending too much time in Summer's skin is dangerous.
你不是冰原狼 布兰
You're not a direwolf, Bran.
不过肯定很棒
Must be glorious, though.
能跑 能跳 能猎食
To run, to leap, to hunt.
身体完整
To be whole.
我知道那很诱人
I know that's tempting,
但是如果你附在夏天身体里太久了
but if you're trapped in Summer for too long,
你会忘了你是人
you'll forget what it was to be human.
你会忘了我们的 布兰
You'd forget us, Bran.
你会忘了你的母亲父亲
You'd forget your mother and father.
忘了你的兄弟姐妹
You'd forget your brothers and sisters.
忘了临冬城
You'd forget Winterfell.
你会忘了你自己
You'd forget you.
我们一旦失去你 就失去了一切
And if we lose you, we lose everything.
夏天
布兰·史塔克的冰原狼
阿多 带我去那棵树那儿
Hodor, take me to the tree.
来找我...
Look for me...
...到这树下面
...beneath the tree.
北方
North.
我知道我们该去哪儿了
I know where we have to go.
玛格丽·提利尔
乔佛里国王的王后
大主教
七神的代言人
我庄严宣布 提利尔家族的玛格丽
Let it be known that Margaery of House Tyrell
与兰尼斯特和拜拉席恩家族的乔佛里结为夫妻
and Joffrey of the Houses Lannister and Baratheon
从今以后 他们就是一个心灵 一个躯体 一个魂魄 直到永远
are one heart, one flesh, one soul.
任何干涉他们婚姻的人
Cursed be he
奥莲娜夫人
玛格丽·提利尔的祖母
洛拉斯·提利尔
“百花骑士”
奥柏伦
“红毒蛇” 多恩亲王
将受到无情的诅咒
who would seek to tear them asunder.
经由这一吻 献出我的爱
With this kiss, I pledge my love.
我们有新王后了
We have a new queen.
她当好过你当啊
Better her than you.
- 有点过了 你觉得呢？ - 很相称
- Bit much, wouldn't you say? - It feels proportionate.
- 与什么相称？ - 预料中的奢侈
- Proportionate to what? - The expected extravagance.
为此种荒谬行为买单的人
People who spend their money on this sort of nonsense
可不希望婚礼持续得太久
tend not to have it for long.
你可得在死之前试着享受点什么
You ought to try enjoying something before you die.
你可能会发现还挺不错的
You might find it suits you.
现在不行 梅斯 泰温大人跟我在说话呢
Not now, Mace. Lord Tywin and I are speaking.
总之 我不知道你在抱怨个啥
Anyway, I don't know what you're complaining about.
我可是付了我的那半了
I'm paying my share.
我们是不是应该把一半的肉派粘上金玫瑰
Shall we stick golden roses in half the meat pies
来表彰您的慷慨？
to commemorate your generosity?
不 你真心的感谢也就足够了
No, your heartfelt thank- you is its own reward.
我猜不久我就会再次听到你的感谢
I would imagine I'd be hearing it again before long.
打仗可是很贵的
Wars are rather expensive.
“铁金库不容拖欠”
"The Iron Bank will have its due.”
它们喜欢提醒大家
How they love to remind everyone.
就像你们兰尼斯特号称有债必偿一样
Almost as much as you Lannisters with your debts.
我可不担心铁金库
I'm not worried about the Iron Bank.
我们都知道你有的是办法
We both know you're smarter than that.
来吧 泰温 让我们庆祝年轻人的爱情
Come, Tywin, let us celebrate young love.
都办好了
All taken care of.
- 你看见她登船了？ - 对 她在上面
- You saw her board the ship? - Aye, she's on it.
你看见船起航了？
You saw the ship sail away?
没人知道她在上面 除了你 我 和瓦里斯
No one knows she's there but you, me, and Varys.
你怎么知道？
How do you know?
因为如果有人跟踪我
Because if someone follows me without an invitation,
那就是他们最后一次跟踪别人了
I'm the last person they ever follow.
有人跟踪你？
There's someone following you?
她走了
She's gone.
我知道你不肯相信 但是她走了
I know you don't want to believe it, but she is.
好了 去喝几口你就没事了
Now, go drink till it feels like you did the right thing.
你好
Hello.
- 你好 - 不是你
- Hello. - Not you.
艾拉莉亚·沙德
奥柏伦的情妇
你看起来格外优雅迷人 孩子
You look exquisite, child.
美中不足的是 风稍稍乱了头发
The wind has been at you, though.
一直没有机会告诉你
I haven't had the opportunity to tell you
对你哥哥的事情我非常遗憾
how sorry I was to hear about your brother.
战争是战争 但是在婚礼上杀人
War is war, but killing a man at a wedding,
太恐怖了
horrid.
什么样的怪物才能干出这种事情来？
What sort of monster would do such a thing?
好像男人对婚姻还不够恐惧似的
As if men need more reasons to fear marriage.
夫人 夫人
My lady. My lady.
你看 嫁给提利昂大人 也没有那么糟糕
Lord Tyrion, you see? Not as bad as all that.
如果嫁给一个穷光蛋
Perhaps if your pauper husband
也许他要卖掉骡子或者最后一双鞋
were to sell his mule and his last pair of shoes,
才能带你去高庭逛一圈
he might be able to afford to bring you to Highgarden for a visit.
现在和平已经到来 世界也都恢复正常了
Now that peace has come and all is right with the world,
到处看看对你也会有好处的
it would do you good to see some of it.
请原谅 我也得去吃点东西了
You must excuse me. It's time I ate
我可是掏过钱的
some of this food I paid for.
♪黄狮子♪
A coat of gold
♪斗红狮子♪
Or a coat of red
♪爪牙锋利不留情♪
A lion still has claws
♪出手…♪
And mine, my lord…
够了 够了 快滚吧
Very good. Very good. Off you go.
亲爱的 不如我们来宣布吧？
My love, why don't we make the announcement?
大家注意
Everyone.
王后有几句话要说
The queen would like to say a few words.
我们如此幸运
We are so fortunate
享受此等的美食美酒
to enjoy this marvelous food and drink.
但是并不是所有人都如我们这般幸运
Not all among us are so lucky.
为感谢诸神保佑战争即将结束
To thank the gods for bringing the recent war to a just end,
乔佛里国王下令将我们婚宴剩下的食物
King Joffrey has decreed that the leftovers
送给他都城里面的穷人
from our feast be given to the poorest in his city.
你真是我们所有人的楷模
You're an example to us all.
詹姆爵士 很抱歉
Ser Jaime, I'm very sorry.
洛拉斯爵士 没关系
Ser Loras, it's quite all right.
你妹妹看起来非常漂亮
Your sister looks very beautiful.
你姐姐也是
As does yours.
这么说 很期待你的婚礼？
So, looking forward to your wedding?
是的 非常期待
Yes, very much.
你我的父亲对两家联姻都非常看好
Our fathers are both rather keen on the prospect.
确实如此
They certainly are.
也许倒是该他们俩结婚
Perhaps they should get married.
你要是娶瑟曦
If you were to marry Cersei,
她会在你睡觉时杀了你的
she'd murder you in your sleep.
你要是莫名其妙地让她怀上孩子
If you somehow managed to put a child in her first,
她会在孩子有第一次呼吸之前
she'd murder him, too,
连孩子也一起杀了
long before he drew his first breath.
对你来说幸运的是 这些都不会发生
Luckily for you, none of this will happen
因为你永远不会娶她
because you'll never marry her.
而你也不会
And neither will you.
布蕾妮·塔斯
“美人”
太后 国王
Your Grace. My king.
- 王后 - 布蕾妮小姐
- My queen. - Lady Brienne.
真高兴你能来
So good of you to come.
我可不是什么小姐 王后
I'm no lady, Your Grace.
你刚刚行的是鞠躬礼？
Did you just bow?
请太后恕罪
Apologies, Your Grace.
我一直都没学会屈膝礼
I never did master the curtsy.
就是你捅了蓝礼·拜拉席恩一剑
You're the one who put a sword through Renly Baratheon.
不是那样的 亲爱的 布蕾妮与此事毫无关系
That's not true, my love. Brienne had nothing to do with it.
真是遗憾
A shame.
谁宰了这变态叛徒 我还想封他个骑士做做
I'd knight the man that put an end to that deviant's life.
我只是想恭喜两位
I just wanted to congratulate you both
祝你们幸福
and wish you good fortune.
这个国家战乱太久了
The country has been at war too long.
我希望你们的结合能够带来长久和平
I hope your reign is long and peaceful.
- 好的 好的 - 谢谢你
- Yes, yes. - Thank you.
我希望能再见到你
I hope we see more of you.
布蕾妮小姐
Lady Brienne.
你是塞尔温·塔斯大人的女儿
You're Lord Selwyn Tarth's daughter.
因此不管愿意与否 你就是一位小姐
That makes you a lady whether you want to be or not.
你说是就是 太后
As you say, Your Grace.
我向你表示感谢
I owe you my gratitude.
你把我弟弟安全地带回了君临
You returned my brother safely to King's Landing.
其实 是他救了我 太后
In truth, he rescued me, Your Grace.
不止一次
More than once.
是吗
Did he?
他都没跟我讲过
Haven't heard that story before.
恐怕 并不是什么光彩的故事
Not such a fascinating story, I'm afraid.
我相信你有很多光彩的故事
I'm sure you have many fascinating stories.
向蓝礼·拜拉席恩效忠 向凯特琳·史塔克效忠 现在又向我弟弟效忠
Sworn to Renly Baratheon. Sworn to Catelyn Stark. And now my brother.
一定很刺激吧 从一个阵营转投到另一个
Must be exciting to flit from one camp to the next
喜欢谁就效忠谁
serving whichever lord or lady you fancy.
我并不效忠于你的弟弟 太后
I don't serve your brother, Your Grace.
但是你爱他
But you love him.
太后
Your Grace.
不不不 到我的房间来 我会亲自给你做检查
No, no, come to my chambers and I will examine you personally.
- 她不会去的 - 哦 太后
- She'll do no such thing. - Oh, Your Grace.
嗯 这位年轻的小姐来找我咨询-
Yes, well, this young lady sought my advice—
你应该去找科本 他很不错
You should see Qyburn. He's quite good.
- 陛下 - 科本？恶心货
- Your Grace. - Qyburn? Deplorable man.
他那些令人作呕的实验丢尽了学城的脸
Brought shame on the Citadel with his repugnant experiments.
比你用皱巴巴的手去摸那个小姑娘的大腿还恶心？
More repugnant than your gnarled fingers on that girl's thighs?
太后 我可是个学士
Your Grace, I am a man of learning.
得罪我小弟的时候他把你扔进了黑牢
My little brother had you sent to the Black Cells when you annoyed him.
你觉得得罪我会怎么样？
What do you think I could do to you if you annoyed me?
我从来不想得罪谁
I never meant to annoy anyone.
但你得罪我了 你现在就得罪我了
But you are. You annoy me right now.
你在这喘口气都是得罪我
Every breath you draw in my presence annoys me.
所以你给我听好了
So here's what I want you to do.
从我眼前消失
I want you to leave my presence.
你现在就从这婚礼上滚蛋
Leave this wedding right now.
滚到厨房去 并且告诉他们
Go to the kitchens and instruct them
所有的剩饭剩菜都给我喂狗
that all the leftovers from the feast will be brought to the kennels.
太后 玛格丽王后 ——
Your Grace, Queen Margaery- -
太后正在命令你
The queen is telling you
所有的剩菜剩饭统统喂狗
the leftovers will feed the dogs
否则就把你喂狗
or you will.
谁能把弄臣的帽子打下来 赏一个金龙
A gold dragon to whoever knocks my fool's hat off.
你心情不错啊
You're in rather a good mood.
- 我想是的 - 不言自明
- I suppose I am. - I won't ask why.
- 小小乐趣罢了 - 陛下 泰温大人
- Small pleasures. - Your Grace. Lord Tywin.
奥柏伦亲王
Prince Oberyn.
我想你们还没见过艾拉莉亚
I don't believe you have met Ellaria.
这位是首相泰温·兰尼斯特大人
This is the Lord Hand Tywin Lannister
和摄政太后瑟曦·兰尼斯特
and Cersei Lannister the Queen Regent.
我想现在应该是前摄政太后了
I suppose it is former Queen Regent now.
首相大人和瑟曦夫人
Lord Hand and Lady Cersei,
- 艾拉莉亚·沙德 - 大人 夫人
- Ellaria Sand. - My lord. My lady.
真迷人
Charmed.
我还从没见过姓沙德的人呢
Can't say I've ever met a Sand before.
在多恩 我们无处不在
We are everywhere in Dorne.
我有成千上万兄弟姐妹
I have 10,000 brothers and sisters.
私生子们都是激情的产物 不是吗
Bastards are born of passion, aren't they?
在多恩 我们从不轻视他们
We don't despise them in Dorne.
是吗？你可真能忍啊
No? How tolerant of you.
我想您这下可轻松了吧 瑟曦夫人
I expect it is a relief, Lady Cersei,
从此就不必再摄政了
giving up your regal responsibilities.
头戴王冠这么多年 您的脖子都被压歪了吧
Wearing the crown for so many years must have left your neck a bit crooked.
这你就永远都不会懂了 奥柏伦亲王
I suppose you'll never know, Prince Oberyn.
你哥哥不能来参加婚礼 真是太可惜了
It's a shame your older brother couldn't attend the wedding.
请替我们对他致以问候
Please give him our regards.
但愿他的痛风能减轻一点
With any luck, the gout will abate
没准他以后还能重新走路呢
with time and he will be able to walk again.
人们都说这可是贵人病
They call it the rich man's disease.
真奇怪您怎么没得呢
A wonder you don't have it.
在我们这地方
Noblemen in my part of the country
贵族们的生活方式可跟你们多恩不一样
don't enjoy the same lifestyle as our counterparts in Dorne.
各地的人们自有不同
People everywhere have their differences.
有些地方贵族们对贫民嗤之以鼻
In some places the highborn frown upon those of low birth.
而有些地方 强奸杀害妇女和婴儿
In other places the rape and murder of women and children
才遭人鄙视
is considered distasteful.
您可真幸运啊 前 摄政太后
What a fortunate thing for you, former Queen Regent,
您的女儿弥赛拉被送往的
that your daughter Myrcella has been sent
是后一类地方
to live in the latter sort of place.
大家安静！ 清出场地
Everyone, silence! Clear the floor.
今天我们的娱乐活动太多了
There's been too much amusement here today.
但是王家婚礼不是玩乐
A royal wedding is not an amusement.
王家婚礼是一段历史
A royal wedding is history.
现在该我们
The time has come for all of us
回顾历史了
to contemplate our history.
大人们…
My lords...
女士们…
my ladies...
有请
I give you
乔佛里国王…
King Joffrey...
…蓝礼 史坦尼斯
...Renly, Stannis,
罗柏·史塔克 巴隆·葛雷乔伊
Robb Stark, Balon Greyjoy.
五王之战
The War of the Five Kings.
我才是合法的国王
I'm the rightful king.
- 北境之王！ - 没错！
- King in the North! - Yes!
叛徒 你这个叛国贼
Traitor. You're a traitor.
为了七国！
For the Seven Kingdoms!
开战吧
Let the war begin.
蓝礼 你才不是国王呢
Renly, you're no king.
滚开 变态 滚开 滚开
Away, degenerate. Away. Away.
小心点
Ooh, careful.
- 继续 - 我封你做亲王
- Go on. - I want you to be my prince.
史坦尼斯！
Stannis!
现在看谁得到金子了 史塔克？
Who's got the gold now, Stark?
我才是合法的国王 来挑战我啊 无赖
I am the rightful king. Challenge me, ruffian.
- 吃我一剑 - 我要淹死了 我要淹死了
- Take that. - I'm drowning. I'm drowning.
我是北境之王！
I am the King in the North!
别放野火！
Not wildfire!
散场之后给他们每人20金龙
Pay each of them 20 gold when this is done.
是 大人
Yes, my lord.
我们还得想想怎么感谢国王才是
We'll have to find another way to thank the king.
冲啊！
Charge!
准备 再来
Ready, again.
我是北境之王！
I am the King in the North!
- 冲啊！- 冲啊！
- Charge! - Charge!
好！
Yes!
你的脑袋！
Your head!
嘉宾们
Fine gentlemen.
打得好 打得好
Well fought. Well fought.
赏你的 冠军的赏钱
Here you are. Champion's purse.
尽管你还不是冠军呢 不是吗？
Though you're not the champion yet, are you?
真正的冠军可击败一切挑战
A true champion defeats all the challengers.
毫无疑问还有其他人
Surely there are others out there
胆敢挑战我的统治
who still dare to challenge my reign.
舅舅
Uncle.
要不你上？我肯定他们有备用服装
How about you? I'm sure they have a spare costume.
我已经尝够了战斗的滋味 陛下
One taste of combat was enough for me, Your Grace.
我的脸上已经不需要再添疤痕了
I would like to keep what remains of my face.
我倒觉得该您上
I think you should fight him.
这场表演完全就是对
This was but a poor imitation
您在战场上英勇形象的拙劣模仿
of your own bravery on the field of battle.
作为第一见证人 我为您不平
I speak as a firsthand witness.
从高台上爬下去
Climb down from the high table
拿着您的新瓦雷利亚宝剑
with your new Valyrian sword
让大家看看 真正的国王是怎样赢得他的王位的
and show everyone how a true king wins his throne.
不过 要当心
Be careful, though.
这人明显已经被情欲逼疯了
This one is clearly mad with lust.
要是国王在大婚前就失身
It would be a tragedy for the king to lose his virtue
那就太悲剧了
hours before his wedding night.
这酒不错
A fine vintage.
洒出来真是糟蹋了
Shame that it spilled.
这不是洒出来的
It did not spill.
亲爱的 回来吧
My love, come back to me.
该我父亲祝酒了
It's time for my father's toast.
我杯中无酒 他怎么祝酒？
Well, how does he expect me to toast without wine?
舅舅 既然你懦弱到不敢战斗的话
Uncle, you can be my cupbearer
来做我的侍酒吧
seeing as you're too cowardly to fight.
谢陛下给我这莫大的荣誉
Your Grace does me a great honor.
这不是荣誉
It's not meant as an honor.
拿我的酒杯来
Bring me my goblet.
我要个空杯子干嘛？
What good is an empty cup?
斟满它
Fill it.
跪下
Kneel.
跪在你的国王面前
Kneel before your king.
跪下
Kneel.
我说…
I said...
跪下！
kneel!
看啊 派来了
Look, the pie.
我的王后
My queen.
太棒了
Wonderful.
我的英雄
My hero.
- 我们能走了吗？ - 我们试试看
- Can we leave now? - Let's find out.
舅舅
Uncle.
你去哪儿？
Where are you going?
你是我的侍酒 记得吗？
You're my cupbearer, remember?
我想我得把这些湿衣服换下来 陛下
I thought I might change out of these wet clothes, Your Grace.
不不不 我看你这样就挺好
No, no, no. No, you're perfect the way you are.
给我斟酒
Serve me my wine.
快点 这派很干
hurry up. This pie is dry.
不错
good.
需要冲下去
Needs washing down.
见谅 陛下 珊莎夫人已经累了
If it please Your Grace, Lady Sansa is very tired.
不行
No.
不行 你在这儿等着…
No, you'll wait here...
陛下？
Your Grace?
没事
It's nothing.
- 他噎住了！ - 帮帮那可怜的孩子
- He's choking! - Help the poor boy.
- 白痴 帮帮你们的国王 - 滚开！
- Idiots, help your king. - Move away!
- 乔佛里！乔佛里！ - 帮帮他！
- Joffrey! Joffrey! - Help him!
- 来人帮帮他！ - 乔佛里！
- Someone help him! - Joffrey!
- 跟我来 - 乔佛里！乔佛里！
- Come with me now. - Joffrey! Joffrey!
想活命的话 我们必须走了
If you want to live, we have to leave.
别碰他！
Don't touch him!
乔佛里
Joffrey.
求求你 乔佛里
Please, Joffrey.
乔佛里 什么？
Joffrey, what is it?
帮帮他！
Help him!
我的儿子
My son.
他走了 我们国王走了
He's gone. Our king is gone.
是他做的
He did this.
他毒死了我儿子
He poisoned my son,
你们的国王
your king.
抓住他 抓住他！
Take him. Take him!
抓住他！
Take him!
衣柜字幕组出品
红狮子
In a coat of gold
斗黄狮子
Or a coat of red
爪牙锋利不留情
A lion still has claws
出手致命招招狠
And mine are long
汝子莫忘记
And sharp, my lord
As long and sharp as yours
他这样说 他这样说
And so he spoke and so he spoke
卡斯特梅的爵爷他这样说
That Lord of Castamere
然而今天 每逢雨季
And now the rains
雨水在大厅哭泣
Weep o'er his hall
内里却无人影
With no one there to hear
然而今天 每逢雨季
Yes, now the rains
雨水在大厅哭泣
Weep o'er his hall
内里却无魂灵
And not a soul to hear.